[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：所以我写了一本关于我使用JavaScript和
&gt;&gt; Douglas: And so I wrote my own book about my experience with JavaScript and
使用JSLint(称为JavaScript)：好的部分。
with JSLint which is called JavaScript: The Good Parts.
令人惊讶的是这本书仍然是一本畅销书
And the surprising thing about this book is it is still a bestseller in
它的类别，这对于软件书籍来说是极其罕见的。
its category, which is extremely rare for software books.
大多数软件书籍在印刷之前就已经过时了，
Most software books are obsolete before they're printed,
这是因为在软件中，事情往往变化和翻滚得太快。
and it's because things tend to change and roll over so quickly in software.
但事实证明，我在这本书中说的话是为了
But it turns out the things that I was saying in this book are for
大部分是对的。
the most part right.
所以它仍然是一本相关的书，尽管JavaScript已经通过了
And so it's still a relevant book even though JavaScript has gone through
两个主要的标准修订版，这本书还是相当不错的。
two major standard revisions, this book is still pretty good.
所以并不是所有人都喜欢它，有很多人反对
So it's not universally adored though, there are lots of arguments against
好的部分的想法，如果可以的话，我想浏览一下其中的一些内容。
the idea of good parts and I'd like to run through some of those if I may.
第一个，这只是一个观点的问题，这是你的观点，
The first one, it's just a matter of opinion, it's your opinion,
我的观点不同，一个观点和另一个观点一样好。
my opinions different, one opinions as good as another.
所以，事实证明并非如此，我是JSLint的维护者。
So there, turns out that's not the case, that I am the maintainer of JSLint.
因此，我收到来自世界各地的人的错误报告，告诉我
And as such I get bug reports from people from all over the world telling me I
刚花了两周时间追查这东西。
just spent two weeks chasing this thing down.
这是由于语言语法中的一些奇怪的边缘情况，
And it was due to some weird edge case in the grammar of the language that
从来没有人注意到，它只是让我们变得残废，
no one had ever noticed, and it just crippled us,
在不好的时候伤害我们，你能让JSLint去找吗？
hurt us at a bad time and could you have JSLint look for that?
因为，如果你能做到，那么其他人就再也不用忍受了。
Cuz, if you can then no one else will ever have to endure that.
所以每当有意义的时候，我都会把这些东西结合起来。
So whenever it makes sense to, I incorporate those things.
所以如果你使用的是JSLint，那么你就永远不会体验到这些东西，
So if you're using JSLint, then you will never experience those things,
这不是意见，这是事实。
that is not an opinion, that is a fact.
每个特征都是必不可少的工具，
Every feature is an essential tool,
我需要所有可用的工具来做我的工作。
I need every tool available in order to do my work.
但是，当我们可以证明您可以通过以下方式编写更好的程序时，那就不是真的了
But that's simply not true when we can show that you can write better programs by
没有使用所有功能。
not using all of the features.
因此，如果您可以在不使用特性的情况下编写更好的程序，则该特性
So if you can write a better program without using a feature that feature
不是必须的。
is not essential.
但这个功能有时很有用，这听起来像是一件重要的事情，
But this feature is sometimes useful and that sounds like an important thing,
我需要能够使用它，因为它有时很有用。
I need to be able to use it because it's sometimes useful.
只是有时候一切都是有用的。
Except it turns out everything is sometimes useful.
你无法辨别出什么东西是如此危险，如此有毒，
You cannot identify anything which is so dangerous, so toxic,
如此令人作呕，那有时也不是很有用。
so disgusting, that is not also sometimes useful.
有时有用是一个强有力的陈述，因为它存在。
Sometimes useful is about as strong a statement as it exists.
听起来远不止这些，但事实并非如此，
It sounds like it's a lot more than that but it isn't,
这实际上不是一个论点。
it actually is not an argument.
因此，如果使用某个功能的原因是因为它有时很有用，
So if the reason for using a feature is because it's sometimes useful,
你根本没有论点。
you simply do not have an argument.
我有权使用每一个功能。
I have a right to use every feature.
现在，在这一点上，争论已经改变了。
Now at this point the argument has changed.
我们不再谈论什么是编写程序的最佳方式，
We're no longer talking about what's the best way to write programs,
我们现在谈论的是我们的权利。
we're now talking about our rights.
而且这听起来真的很重要和正义，谈论权利和
And it sounds really important and righteous to be talking about rights and
为[声音]辩护，除非你遵循这个论点得出结论。
defending [SOUND], except if you follow this argument to its conclusion.
最终是这样的，你有权写垃圾吗？
Ultimately it goes like this, do you have the right to write crap?
是的，我有权写垃圾。
Yes I have the right to write crap.
所以现在我们争论的是你有权写垃圾是真的还是
So now we're arguing about do you have the right to write crap is that true or
不，我不知道，我不在乎这不重要。
not, I don't know, I don't care it's not important.
更重要的是你有责任
What's more important is you have a responsibility to
编写工作良好且没有错误的代码。
write code that works well and is free of error.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯：我需要表达自己的自由，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: I need the freedom to express myself,
我是一个诗人，因为我表达我的诗歌的方式是省略我的分号。
I'm a poet in the way I express my poetry is by leaving out my semicolons.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：我需要减少我的击键次数。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: I need to reduce my keystrokes.
这真的是一个非常阴险的大事件，因为我们
This is a really insidious one big again because we
想象一下，我们把大部分时间都花在打字上，但我们没有。
imagine that we spend most of our time typing but we don't.
所以如果你把一年内完成的所有干净的代码，
So if you were to take all the clean finished code you finish in a year,
你可以在一天内打出来。
you could type it in a day.
所以这就提出了一个问题，你用剩下的99%的时间在做什么？
So that raises a question, what are you doing with the other 99% of your time?
击键不是重要的事情。
Keystrokes is not the important thing.
如果我能想出一个办法让你的击键次数增加十倍
If I could figure out a way to increase your keystrokes by a factor of ten and
将你的错误减半，那将是一个巨大的胜利。
cut your errors in half, that would be a huge win.
不幸的是，我没有那个公式
Unfortunately, I don't have that formula for
你，但这就是我们要看的比率。
you but that's the sort of ratios we're looking at.
暗示我会犯错误是一种侮辱
It is an insult to suggest that I would ever make a mistake with
一个危险的特征。
a dangerous feature.
低人一等的人显然会因为这样做而产生问题，但是
Inferior people could obviously have problems by doing that but
我必须有满足感。
I must have satisfaction.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：然后有一个很好的理由添加这些功能
&gt;&gt; Douglas: And then there's a good reason those features were added
对于语言，我可以根据经验告诉你，这绝对不是真的。
to the language and I can tell you from experience, that is absolutely not true.
我见过事情是如何被转换成语言的，而这些事情发生在
I've seen how things get put into languages, and those things happen for
各种各样的原因，但并不是所有的原因都是好的。
all kinds of reasons, and they're not all good ones.
JavaScript的创建者Brendan Eich谈到了脚枪。
The creator of JavaScript, Brendan Eich talks about foot guns.
步枪是你用来射自己脚的语言的一种特征
A foot gun is a feature of the language that you use to shoot yourself in the foot
[声音]他把很多东西放在JavaScript里，我想他后悔了。
[SOUND] and he put a lot of those in JavaScript and I think he regrets it.
他会不时地告诉标准委员会，
And from time to time he would tell the standards committee,
我们不要再增加太多的步枪，他们并不总是听他的。
let's not be adding too many more foot guns and they don't always listen to him.
所以你总能找到更多但是
So you can always find more but
有些人看起来(声音)，我几乎总是怀念看这个。
there are guys who look [SOUND], I almost always miss watch this.
&gt；&gt；[声音]&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑声]
&gt;&gt; [SOUND] &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：[笑]所以
&gt;&gt; Douglas: [LAUGH] So
编程语言的目的是帮助程序员
the purpose of a programming language is to aid programmers in
制作无错误的程序，这就是全部。
producing error-free programs, that's the whole deal.
所以我们过去认为不可能用
So we used to think that it was not possible to write good programs in
JavaScript是因为它的语言太混乱了，根本不可能，所以
JavaScript because the language was such a mess that just wasn't possible, so
甚至没有理由去尝试。
no reason to even try.
原来那不是真的
Turned out that was not true that
用JavaScript编写好的程序不仅是可能的，而且是必要的。
it is not only possible to write good programs in JavaScript, it is necessary.
使用这种需要的语言很容易脱轨
It is so easy to go off the rails with this language it requires
巨大的纪律，也许比任何其他语言都更有纪律。
tremendous discipline, maybe more discipline than any other language.
所以当你使用这种语言的时候，你真的必须带上它。
So you really have to bring it when you're using this language.
所以在JavaScript中仍然有很多关于Java的混淆，因为
So there's a lot of confusion still about Java in JavaScript because
他们看起来有点相似，他们有相同的名字。
they kind of look similar and they have the same name.
有时我被介绍为Java专家
Sometimes I'm introduced as a Java experts which I am but
我经常被邀请是因为我是JavaScript专家
I'm usually invited because I'm a JavaScript expert and
这类似于我们在“星际迷航”和“星球大战”之间的混淆。
it's similar to the confusion we have between Star Trek and Star Wars.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：我们有两门科学
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: We've got two science
名称基本相同的小说专营权。
fiction franchises with basically the same name.
从十英尺外看，他们看起来有点像同一个节目。
And from ten feet away, they kinda look like the same show.
但我们知道它们不是一回事，对吧？
But we know they're not the same thing, right?
差别真的很大。
The differences are really significant.
在“星际迷航”中，你有相位器和光子鱼雷，
In Star Trek, you've got phasers, and photon torpedoes,
你有制服，羽绒规则，所有的规则，对吧？
you've got uniforms, down regulations, everything's regulations, right?
而在“星球大战”中，你有轻型军刀和爆破枪。
Whereas in Star Wars, you've got light sabres and blasters.
你有质子鱼雷，完全不同的鱼雷。
You've got proton torpedoes, completely different torpedoes.
你有沙子，我不喜欢沙子和混乱。
You've got sand, I don't like sand and chaos.
所以你知道哪一个是JavaScript，
So you know which one of these is JavaScript,
显然“星球大战”是对的。
well obviously Star Wars right.
事实上，当您使用JavaScript时，
In fact when you're working with JavaScript,
JavaScript为您提供了一个选择。
JavaScript presents you with a choice.
你可以去绝地或者你可以去加。
You can go Jedi or you can go Jar Jar.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：和
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: And
我们的兄弟中有相当多的人喜欢去果酱。
quite a lot of our brothers like to go Jar Jar so.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas：SO
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: So
我观察到的一件事，我观察到的两件事是永不出错的幻想
one thing I've observed, two things I've observed are the fantasy of infallibility
以及无懈可击的徒劳。
and the futility of faultlessness.
我看到了无懈可击的幻想，特别是在年轻人身上，
I see the fantasy of infallibility especially in younger guys,
他们认为自己有这样的技能。
who think they have such that skills.
他们可以在里面写任何垃圾然后他们就能逃脱惩罚，
That they can write just any crap in it and they're gonna get away with it,
他们可以做傻事，一切都会好起来的。
that they can just do stupid and that it's gonna be all right.
然后，无懈可击的徒劳，我在年长的人中看到的更多。
Then, the futility of faultlessness, I see this more among older guys.
男人们已经做了很长时间了。
Guys have been doing this for a long time.
我从来没有见过一个女孩写东西，它永远不会正确，为什么还要尝试呢？
I've never seen a girl write, it's never gonna go right, why even try?
这是两个非常不同的观点，但它们都导致了同样的事情。
Just so two very different perspectives but they both lead to the same thing.
危险驱动的开发，在代码中做疯狂而鲁莽的事情
Danger driven development where you doing crazy reckless stuff in the code
只是为了保持它的趣味性，因为嘿，我们不这样做。
just to keep it interesting cuz hey we don't do that.
别忘了带分号，对吧。
And don't forget your semicolons, right.
所以让编程很难管理的一件事是，
So one of the things that makes programming difficult to manage,
调度的困难。
is the difficulty of scheduling.
通常当我们做某事的时候，我们这样做是为了
That usually when we're doing something, we're doing it for
这是我们第一次这么做
the first time we've ever done it.
所以我们不知道，我们不可能知道要花多长时间，但是
And so we don't know, there's no way we could know how long it's gonna take but
我们将进行猜测和我们的猜测。
we'll make guesses and our guesses.
因为我们是乐观主义者通常都是大错特错的，但是
Cuz we're optimists are usually wildly wrong but
事情就是这样，但更难的是安排第二次。
that's the way it goes but what's even harder is scheduling the second time.
这是时间B，使代码正确工作所需的时间，
Which is the time B, the time it takes to make the code work right,
现在应该是零，对吧。
now that should be zero right.
你应该写它，它应该是正确的，我们就完成了。
You should write it and it should be right and we're done.
但事实并非如此，时间B通常大于时间A，
But that's not the case, that often time B is greater than time A,
我见过时间B是无限的情况。
I've seen cases where time B is infinite.
这就是当代码完成时发生的事情，但是
That's what happens when the codes finished but
然后项目在他们开始工作之前就被取消了。
then the project is cancelled before they can get it to work.
实际上，这种情况发生得太频繁了，所以如果你及时做任何事情
That happens way too often actually, so if you do anything in time
这增加了时间B变大的可能性，你做错了。
A that increases the likelihood of time B being bigger, you're doing it wrong.
这不是节省时间的时候。
That's not the time to be saving time.
因此，我们应该总是花时间编写好代码。
So we should always take the time to code well.
有时会有这样的想法，好吧，我们只是快速地做这件事
Sometimes there's this idea that, well we're just doing this quick and
肮脏的东西，所以让我们只是非常草率，并尽快完成它。
dirty thing so let's just be really sloppy and get it done fast.
除了完成它还意味着它必须工作
Except getting it done still means it has to work and
如果你写得好，让它工作仍然会更容易。
getting it to work is still going to be easier if you write it well.
写好它所花费的时间将会更少
That the time it takes to write it well is going to be less time that
如果写得不好，需要让它正确工作。
takes to make it work right if it's not written well.